A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the Vice President, Media Projects, Office Files of Andrea L. Taylor FA684
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Media Projects, 1971-1999; 5; 15 Cubic Feet 39 letter document boxes and 1 half-box
  - National Hispanic Media Coalition, Los Angeles County Latino Assessment Study, 1989-1990 (Box 32, Folder 420)
  - National Museum of Women in the Arts, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 421)
  - Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation - New Chance: A New Initiative for Adolescent Mothers and Their Children, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 422)
  - Nicaragua In Transit Proposal, Bianca Jagger, Livet Reichard Company, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 423)
  - Paul Gray's Film Directing Seminar, 1990-1991 (Box 32, Folder 424)
  - People Matter, Series on Human Rights: Advise Foundation, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 425)
  - People with AIDS Coalition, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 426)
  - Proposal for an Education Program - Perspectives on Peace in the Middle East, The University of Texas at Austin, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 427)
  - Perlstein Foundation, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 428)
  - Corporation for Public Broadcasting - Minority Writers Conference on TV Production, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 429)
  - Children's Television Workshop, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 430)
  - Changing Relations - Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 34, Folder 431)
  - Grantmakers in Film, Television, and Video Meeting, 1992 November 16 (Box 34, Folder 432)
  - Funders Interested in Film and Video - Meeting and Attendees Records, 1990 June 29 (Box 34, Folder 433, Box 35, Folder 434-435)
  - Funders Interested in Film and Video (Council on Foundations Affinity Group) Meetings, 1990-1991 (Box 35, Folder 436-437)
  - Funders Interested in Film and Video - Meeting, 1992 June (Box 36, Folder 438-439)
  - WCHR City College/Harlem Community Radio Annual Report, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 440)
  - Black Agency Executives, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 441)
  - Grantee: Academy for Educational Developmental, Inc - National Public Broadcasting Archive, 1990 (Box 36, Folder 442)
  - Luis Nogales Ford Foundation Trustee Press Release, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 443)
  - Learning Link - Georgia Public TV and LinkNet, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 444)
  - Letter from Gail M. Leftwich, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 445)
  - NYU Substance Abuse Program Press Release (Bill Grinker), 1991 (Box 36, Folder 446)
  - Sandra J. Hale - Resume Package, 1987-1991 (Box 36, Folder 447)
  - National Women of Color Organizations - Mailing, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 448)
  - Empowering Disadvantaged Groups: Rights and Opportunities for Women and Blacks in Brazil, Rebecca Reichmann, 1990 (Box 36, Folder 449)
  - Women's Program Forum - Women in Media, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 450)
  - Work/Family Task Force Report, 1988-1990 (Box 37, Folder 451)
  - George Curry, Chicago Tribune - Writing Samples, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 472)
  - Indiana University Black Film Center/Archive, Portia Maultsby, 1989-1990 (Box 40, Folder 473)
  - Communications Plan for 1990, 1989-1990 (Box 40, Folder 474)
  - CNN Business News - Pinnacle, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 475)
  - Zuniga, Frank, Crosscurrents Institute - Human Rights and Governance, 1988-1989 (Box 40, Folder 476)
  - Work/Family Task Force, Sub-committee on the Nature of Jobs, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 477)
  - Leaf Productions - Poverty in Texas: An American Family, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 478)
  - Keys Educators Broadcasting (Florida Non-Profit Corporation), 1988-1989 (Box 40, Folder 479)
  - Karamu House, Cleveland - The Role of the Arts in Human Relations, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 480)
  - Kansas State University Western Task Force Meeting, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 481)
    Ford Grant #89-131
  - Grameen Bank - Notes, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 482)
  - Memo - Publication for the 40th Anniversary in India, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 483)
  - Educational Videos for Hungary, Martin Sandler, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 484)
  - Emergency Housing Apartment Program (EHAP) Press Release, 1987-1988 (Box 40, Folder 485)
  - Horizon Communications - Problem Solving Symposia, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 486)
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation Trip File, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 487)
  - Correspondence Regarding Ford Publication on Hispanic Theater in the United States, Puerto Rico Community Foundation, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 488)
  - Handbook of Organizations Involved in Soviet-American Relations Correspondence, Institute for Soviet-American Relations, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 489)
  - Letters/Memos from Brian Wenham, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 490)
  - Our World: Challenges and Choices (Intention, Format, Style, etc.), 1989 (Box 41, Folder 491)
  - Our World: Challenges and Choices, BBC TV Series Outline, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 492)
  - Hall of the States Venue, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 493)
  - Corporation for Public Broadcasting Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 41, Folder 494)
  - Black Ivory: The Pan-African Magazine, 1989-1990 (Box 41, Folder 495)
  - David T. Kearns, Trustee, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 496)
  - Governor Milliken - Champions of Good Government Right in Our Own Backyards, Op-Ed Piece, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 497)
  - Ford Foundation Trustees - Press Release Drafts, 1989-1991 (Box 41, Folder 498)
  - Current Events Film Correspondence, Ralph Arlyck, Timed Exposures, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 499)
  - Press Coverage of Foreign Crises: The Tiananmen Square Massacre Conference, Harvard, 1991 April-May (Box 41, Folder 500)
  - 1989 Annual Corporate Affiliates Program Symposium, University Corporation for Atmospheric Research (Box 41, Folder 501)
  - Men of Color-To Arms, Jacqueline Shearer, Reel Deal Production Company, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 502)
    Premiered on PBS as "The Massachusetts 54th Colored Infantry," American Experience
  - Andrea Taylor - Bios, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 503)
  - American Public Radio (APR) - Multicultural Programming into the Next Century Symposium, 1989 November (Box 41, Folder 504)
  - American Public Radio (APR) Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 41, Folder 505)
  - The Fading Fortunes of the Quiet Army Proposal, MainStreet Productions, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 506)
  - Institute for Fiduciary Education, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 507)
  - SEEDS Pamphlet Series on Women's Income-Generating Projects: Population Council Meeting, 1990 July (Box 41, Folder 508)
  - SEEDS Steering Committee Meeting, 1990 March 8 (Box 41, Folder 509)
  - Sundance Institute Letters, 1989-1990 (Box 42, Folder 510)
  - Sundance Meetings, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 511)
  - Sundance RGA - Support for Dance/Film Laboratory, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 512)
  - Rocky Mountain Institute (Sundance Institute), 1989 (Box 42, Folder 513)
    Grant #885-0753
  - Reach New England Magazine, F. Joseph Rogers - Meeting/Franklin A. Thomas, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 514)
  - Vineyard Video Productions - You May Call Her Madam Secretary, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 515)
  - VITA (Volunteers in Technical Assistance), 1988-1990 (Box 42, Folder 516)
  - Roger Wade Productions: Ford Foundation Orientation Program, 1988-1989 (Box 42, Folder 517)
  - Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture Convocation at Riverside Church, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 518)
  - Society for International Development (SID) - World Conference, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 519)
  - Smithsonian Institution - Archivist Vacancy Announcements, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 520)
  - Henry Ramos (Consultant) - Evaluation of Grant to Bay Area Institute, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 521)
  - Media Training - Shepard Forman, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 522)
  - South Carolina Educational Television - International Public Television (INPUT) Screening Conference, Stockholm, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 523)
  - Ford Foundation Summer Internship Program, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 524)
  - Timothy Puin, Summer Intern, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 525)
  - Kwyn Bader, Summer Intern, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 526)
  - Women in the Media Conference - PBS Rocky Mountain Retreat, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 527)
  - Sundance - Soviet Film Project, Earthwatch, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 528)
  - International Women's Media Foundation - Film Meeting, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 529)
  - "Chico Mendes" - Miranda Smith Productions and Better World Society, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 530)
  - Marva Collins Westside Preparatory School Foundation, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 531)
  - Martin Sandler Productions - Promoting the Common Good: Excellence in the Public Sector, 1988-1989 (Box 43, Folder 532)
  - NAACP - General Correspondence, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 533)
  - Museum of Afro-American History, African Meeting House, Boston, Massachusetts - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 534)
  - World Congress of Black Intellectuals, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 535)
  - National Association of Black Journalists, 1988-1989 (Box 43, Folder 536)
  - Broadcast News - V. S. Naipaul, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 537)
  - National Wildlife Federation - Decade of Destruction, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 538)
  - National Urban/Rural Fellows, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 539)
  - National Committee on American Foreign Policy, 1990 March (Box 43, Folder 540)
  - National Civic League - John Parr, 1990-1991 (Box 43, Folder 541)
  - Indian Health Board of Minneapolis, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 542)
  - Ford Foundation Letter - Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation, 1991 (Box 43, Folder 543)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation - Franklin Thomas Remarks at the 10th Anniversary Celebration, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 544)
  - Joint Center for Political Studies, Mark Lloyd, 1989-1990 (Box 43, Folder 545)
  - Focus Magazine, Joint Center for Political Studies, 1988-1989 (Box 43, Folder 546)
  - Film Forum - Karen Cooper, 1991 (Box 43, Folder 547)
  - Third World Television Exchange, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 548)
  - Martha Stuart Communications - Proposal to Develop Video Activities on Gender Issues in Bangladesh, 1986-1990 (Box 43, Folder 549)
  - The Media-Advertising Partnership for a Drug-Free America Grant, 1991 (Box 43, Folder 550)
  - Meadows Foundation - Benton Foundation American Assembly on Public Policy for American Television Outline, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 551)
  - Rural Poverty, Marengo County, Alabama Film - David Wilson, Rutgers University, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 552)
  - Cleveland Workshop on Environmental Reporting, Scientists' Institute for Public Information, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 553)
  - Ms. Foundation, 1989-1991 (Box 43, Folder 554)
  - Her Giveaway: A Spiritual Journey with AIDS, The Minneapolis Foundation, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 555)
  - Roberto Marinho Foundation, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 556)
  - Planet Live - Earthbeat, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 557)
  - Northwest Area Foundation - National Native News, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 558)
  - Producers International Corporation - Documentary on Philanthropy, Center on Philanthropy, Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 559)
  - Panos Institute - International Conference on the Role of the Church in Addressing AIDS, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 560)
  - 1990 Peabody Award Winners (Box 43, Folder 561)
  - Pantheon Books - Vernon Jordan, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 562)
  - Palmetto Broadcasters Associates and Keys Educators Broadcasting - Hispanic News Program, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 563)
  - Nieman Foundation and the African-American Institute - Africa and Central Europe: The Media Strengthening Democratic Institutions Conference, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 564)
  - Owen Ryan and Associates - Constance Sampson, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 565)
  - Steuart Osha, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 566)
  - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 567)
  - Doubleday - Changing Relations Research Questions, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 568)
  - Ford Foundation Publications Sent Out, 1989-1990 (Box 44, Folder 569)
  - Native Americans in Philanthropy (NAP) Annual Meeting, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 570)
  - New York State Council on the Arts, 1988-1989 (Box 44, Folder 571)
  - North American Precis Syndicate, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 572)
  - Institute of Noetic Sciences Temple Award for Creative Altruism, 1989-1990 (Box 44, Folder 573)
  - New York University Drug Program, William Grinker, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 574)
  - New York University Film School, George Stoney, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 575)
  - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers - Public Communication Subcommittee (Michael Seltzer), 1991 (Box 44, Folder 576)
  - Outreach Campaign for the Project on Hemispheric Cooperation for the Prevention of Drug Abuse and Traffic, Institute of the Americas, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 577)
  - The Science Museum of Minnesota - Tropical Rainforest OMNIMAX Film Project, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 578)
  - Bill Moyers, Public Affairs Television, 1987-1988 (Box 44, Folder 579)
  - Education and Culture: Toward a New Professorate: A Review of the Ford Foundation Initiative in Undergraduate Education, 1990-1991 (Box 44, Folder 580)
  - New Voices Radio - Community Network, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 581)
  - W.K. Kellogg Foundation - Ford Pamphlet Request, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 582)
  - International Radio and Television Foundation, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 583)
  - Friedrich-Naumann-Stiftung Foundation - Roundtable Discussion Invitations, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 584)
  - Louis B. Mayer Foundation, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 585)
  - Foundation for Global Broadcasting, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 586)
  - CRB Foundation, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 587)
  - Una Chapman Cox Foundation - Films on Foreign Service and Public Service, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 588)
  - 1991 Leadership Program for Community Foundations, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 589)
  - Community Foundation for Southeastern Michigan - Covering Territory: Community Foundation Area Funds and Affiliates, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 590)
  - Epstein, Gutzwiller, and Partners, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 591)
  - School of Journalism, Columbia University - Minority Recruitment, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 592)
  - Alfred I. duPont-Columbia University Award - WGBH Inside Gorbachev's USSR, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 593)
  - Duke University - The Fundamental Questions of Innovation Conference, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 594)
  - North Carolina Department of Administration, Agency for Telecommunications, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 595)
  - Corrective Capitalism (Publication) Correspondence, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 596)
  - Council of New York Law Associates, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 597)
  - Council on Community-Based Development Documentary Project, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 598)
  - Foundation for American Communities (FACS), 1988-1991 (Box 45, Folder 599)
  - Community Renewal Team (CRT), 1989 (Box 45, Folder 600)
  - Committee to Protect Journalists, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 601)
  - Council of Community-Based Development - From the Bottom Up Documentary, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 602)
  - Benton Foundation and Children's Campaign Consortium - Strategy Session on Children's Issues, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 603)
  - The Benton Foundation - American Assembly on Public Policy for American Television and General Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 45, Folder 604)
  - Cannes Film Festival, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 605)
  - Hawaii Film Festival - Curriculum Guide Project, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 606)
  - The Documentary Festival of New York, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 607)
  - International Public Television Screening Conference 1991 Dublin, 1990-1991 (Box 45, Folder 608)
  - Margaret Mead Film Festival, American Museum of Natural History, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 609)
  - Native American Film and Video Festival, National Museum of the American Indian Promotional Letter, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 610)
  - Festival dei Popoli - International Review of Social Documentary Film, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 611)
  - PanAfrican Film and Television Festival, Ouagadougou, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 612)
  - Santa Fe Native American Producer's Conference, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 613)
  - Film Festivals, 1989-1990 (Box 45, Folder 614)
  - Sarasota French Film Festival, 1990 November (Box 46, Folder 615)
  - Sundance Film Festival, 1989-1991 (Box 46, Folder 616)
  - Glasnost Film Festival, 1988-1989 (Box 46, Folder 617)
  - The Washington, D.C. Film Festival/Becoming American, Changing Relations Project, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 618)
  - FESPACO, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 619)
  - Hawaii International Film Festival, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 620)
  - Stand and Deliver, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 621)
  - Articles on Black Philanthropy by Emmett D. Carson, Joint Center for Political Studies' Project on Black Philanthropy, 1987-1989 (Box 46, Folder 622)
  - The Explorer's Pass: A Report on Case Studies of Girls and Math, Science and Technology, Girls Incorporated, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 623)
  - African Meeting House, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 624)
  - South Africa Now, 1989-1990 (Box 52, Folder 685)
  - South Africa Trip, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 686)
  - South Africa - Zimbabwe Trip File, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 687)
  - South Africa Trip File - Dr. Jonathan N. Moyo, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 688)
  - The Nieman Foundation/African-American Institute Media Conference, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 689)
    The Independent Media in a Changing South and Southern Africa
  - South Africa Trip File - Notes, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 690)
  - South Africa Media Program Activities, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 691)
  - Native American Task Force/Ad Hoc Committee on American Indians, 1990-1993 (Box 52, Folder 692, Box 53, Folder 693-694)
  - Sundance Institute, 1991-1994 (Box 58, Folder 718)
  - New Images Productions - Simple Justice Film, 1992-1994 (Box 58, Folder 719)
  - New Images Productions - Omega Boys Club and Street Soldiers, 1994-1995 (Box 58, Folder 720)
  - Philanthropy and the Digital Age presented by National Video Resources, Inc., Esther Dyson, 1996 April 9 (Box 59, Folder 721)
  - OMB Watch, 1994 (Box 59, Folder 722)
  - Satyajit Ray Project - Living Film Archive, 1993-1994 (Box 59, Folder 723)
  - The Global Fund for Women - Network Communications Project, 1993 (Box 59, Folder 724)
  - The Chronicle of Philanthropy - Articles and Ford Memos, 1995 (Box 59, Folder 725)
  - The Freedom Forum Media Studies Center, 1993-1995 (Box 59, Folder 726)
  - The Film Society of Lincoln Center - Arab Cinema Film Series and Outreach, 1993-1995 (Box 59, Folder 727)
  - The MEE Report: Reaching the Hip-Hop Generation, MEE Productions Inc., Philadelphia, Research Division, 1993 (Box 60, Folder 728)
  - Panos Institute, 1993-1995 (Box 60, Folder 729)
  - The Southern Center for International Studies, 1991-1995 (Box 60, Folder 730)
  - Charles Hobson, Vanguard Films - African Media Consultant, The New Africa, 1994 (Box 60, Folder 731)
  - Video Placement Worldwide - Investing for Social Gain Project, 1993-1995 (Box 60, Folder 732)
  - Watts Labor Community Action Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 60, Folder 733)
  - Interactive Media/Communications Technology, 1995 (Box 60, Folder 734)
  - Talk Radio Research Proposal, Annenberg School for Communication, 1995 (Box 60, Folder 735)
  - WGBH African American Television Summit, 1992-1993 (Box 60, Folder 736, Box 61, Folder 737)
  - 1995 United Nations World Conference on Women, Beijing, 1993-1995 (Box 61, Folder 738)
- Council on Foundations, 1990-1993; 6; 2.28 Cubic Feet 6 letter document boxes
  The Council on Foundations is a nonprofit membership association founded in 1949 to provide tools and leadership opportunities for philanthropic organizations.
  The series consists of correspondence, meeting notes, conference materials, reports, and articles created by various groups within the Council on Foundations, including the Technology Task Force, Grantmakers in Film, TV, and Video, and the Education Committee.
  - Technology Task Force - Interactive Demographic Media Project, 1991 September (Box 37, Folder 452)
  - Technology Task Force - Technology Study Group, 1991-1992 (Box 37, Folder 453)
  - Technology Task Force - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 454)
  - Conference Memos, 1990-1993 (Box 37, Folder 455)
  - Quarter Reports, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 456)
  - Council Columns, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 457)
  - Communications Update (Publication), 1992 (Box 38, Folder 458)
  - Press Release - Film and Video Festival at 1993 Annual Conference in Dallas (Box 38, Folder 459)
  - 1993 Annual Conference, 1992-1993 (Box 38, Folder 460-461)
  - Grantmakers in Film, Television and Video - Conferences, 1991-1993 (Box 38, Folder 462)
  - Affinity Groups Contact List, 1990-1992 (Box 38, Folder 463)
  - Grantmakers in Film, TV, and Video - Meeting Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 39, Folder 464)
  - Grantmakers in Film, TV, and Video - Various Articles, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 465)
  - Grantmakers Infrastructure Task Force, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 466)
  - Grantmakers in Film, TV, and Video - Steering Committee, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 467)
  - Grantmakers in Film, TV, and Video - Intelsat, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 468)
  - Education Committee Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 39, Folder 469)
  - Education Committee - Meeting, Washington, D.C., 1992 January 13-14 (Box 39, Folder 470)
  - Education Committee - Meeting, Washington, D.C., 1991 June 20-21 (Box 40, Folder 471)
  - Film and Video Festival, 1991-1993 (Box 50, Folder 678-680)
  - Education Committee, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 681)
  - Background, Communications Material, Conferences, and Quarterly Publication, 1992-1993 (Box 51, Folder 682-684)
- Correspondence Files, 1993-1996; 7; 2.09 Cubic Feet 6 containers
  The series consists of Andrea Taylor's correspondence files written and received between 1993 and 1996. The letters are arranged alphabetically within each folder.
  - Correspondence Files, 1993 October-1994 December (Box 53, Folder 695, Box 54, Folder 696-699, Box 55, Folder 700-701)
  - 1993 Correspondence, 1993 May 7 (Box 56, Folder 702)
    Memo - Draft of FY 1994 and 1995 Program for Media Projects
  - 1994 Correspondence, 1994 January-February (Box 56, Folder 703)
    Delegated Authority Grants (DAG) to two radio series on reproductive health and population
  - 1995 Correspondence, 1995 January-March (Box 56, Folder 704-705)